## SHANE O'NEILL WEB DEVELOPER

### CONTACT



Lucan, Co.Dublin, Ireland.



+353 (0) 83 471 3154



Shaneoneill1995@gmail.com



www.shaneoneill.eu

### EDUCATION

### Bachelor of Science

First Class Honours – Honours in Computing - Evening National College of Ireland 2016-2020

### Certificate of Completion

Bitcoin 101, Ethereum 101, React.JS, Smart contract programming completion - Ivan on tech academy

### EXPERTISE

**Project Management** 

Web Development

Cryptocurrencies

Interpersonal Skills

Blockchain Development

Communication Skills

### About Me

From the moment I produced "Hello World" in the console of my first application, I knew I was hooked into the world of development. But web development has never been "just a job" for me, it has offered me an engaging challenge to continually learn and improve my skills in creating high quality, user-oriented web applications. What started with my first HTML landing page has developed into a fully-fledged passion that only gets more exciting and engaging as time goes on.

Expanding my knowledge into frameworks like React etc. has been an interesting personal development and challenged me to rethink my approach to web development.

### **Projects**

### TraFiGuard - video link

Trafiguard is a project aimed at creating a decentralized platform for SMEs to obtain trade finance for global shipments.

<u>Built with</u>: Chainlink, Compound, Solidity, Bloom & React.

### PresChain - Link

This project is an attempt to use NFTs as a way to tokenize drug prescriptions on the Ethereum blockchain.

<u>Built with</u>: Solidity, MetaMask, Coinbase Wallet, AWS.

### Canada Life Re - Canadalifere.com

This website was built and is the production website for Canada Life Reinsurance dac.

Built with: Joomla, Blacknight, HTML & CSS

### My Portfolio - shaneoneill.eu

This website is my personal website and portfolio. This site is updated regularly so be sure to check back or send me a message in the form at the bottom.

<u>Built with</u>: APIs, Flask, Python, JavaScript & Twilio.

### Technologies

Solidity	React.js	Web3.js
Ethereum	JavaScript	Chainlink
Python	Bitcoin	HTML/CSS

### Certification

### Ivan On Tech Academy:

- Blockchain and Bitcoin 101
- Bitcoin Attacks
- Bitcoin Programming
- > C++ Programming for Blockchain Developers
- JavaScript Programming for Blockchain Developers
- EOS Programming 101
- Ethereum Smart Contract Programming 101
- > Ethereum Smart Contract Programming 201
- React Web Development 101

# Customer Relations Conscientious Administration Team Objective Player Driven Adaptable TRAITS

SKILLS

**CREATIVE** 

PEOPLE PERSON

CONSCIENTIOUS

DEDICATED

SENSE OF HUMOUR

INTELLIGENT

QUICK TO LEARN

### **Employment History**

### **Great West Life Europe | End-User Technology**

January 2020 - Present

### Key Responsibilities:

- > Oversee the transition of IT services from Canada Life Re to GWLE.
- Office 365 and Windows 10 roll out project.
- > Licencing management and compliance.
- Disaster recovery and BCP testing.

# Canada Life Reinsurance | Network Administrator / Support Engineer

September 2017 - December 2019

### **Key Responsibilities:**

- > Development of the canadalifere.com website
- Full implementation of machine imaging software to automate and streamline the machine build process using OS Deploy.
- Full transition of all computers to windows 10 from windows 7.
- > Full transition of user fleet to office 365.
- Server maintenance and upgrades.
- Weekly and Monthly Backups of server fleet.
- SQL Server management.
- Transition of Services to GWLE of entire computer and server fleet

   included a reimaging and transfer of all servers and computers
   in the CLRE domain.
- Office move including the moving of all Server equipment and IT Hardware to new office.
- Disaster recovery and BCP testing

### **Irish Aviation Authority | IT Support Engineer**

October 2015 – August 2017

### Key Achievements:

- Full transition of desktop and laptop fleet to Windows 10.
- > Full transition of users and machines to office 365 user base of over 1000.
- Implementation of imaging system to automate and streamline machine build and roll-out processes using DELL KACE.
- > Full Revamp of Pilot exam room with new computers access points and peripherals.
- > Full revamp of audio/visual systems in all conference rooms.

### Achievements and Interests

- Added to the Deans Honor list for > 70% grade average in 3<sup>rd</sup> year of college NCI.
- Great Knowledge of Crypto Currency and world finance.
- Final Year College project Prescriptions on Ethereum, distribution of prescriptions to patients via Ethereum via ERC721 asset token standard.
- I have a heavy interest in crypto and blockchain, and other emerging technologies. I have studied Bitcoin and other crypto projects in great detail and have a good working knowledge of Ethereum and smart contract platforms.

### REFERENCES-Available on Request